Speaker: How to make London more friendly
London is the least friendly city in the UK, or that’s what a recent survey says.
I’ve lived in London all my life, and I love my city,
but it’s true that in a big city people aren’t always as friendly as they could be.
So what can we do to get a better reputation?
Here are my six tips.
The first tip is for commuters on the London Underground,
and it is: be understanding of other people.
Not everybody uses the Tube every day to go to work,
so not everybody knows the rules,
for example, on an escalator, stand on the right, but walk up or down on the left.
Some people are on the Tube because they’re tourists
who want to go to Buckingham Palace.
So be understanding! Don’t make a face at them – smile!
My second tip is for local people like me, or anybody who knows London well.
If a tourist asks you for directions, be patient.
You’re very lucky that they are making an effort to speak to you in English.
We British mostly can’t speak any other language than our own.
When we’re abroad we expect other people to understand us,
and most of the time, they’ll give it a try.
So when they ask you for help, be patient and help them.
Repeat the directions if necessary.
Maybe even try to learn another language!
My third tip is for car drivers.
Try to relax.
Yes, you are stuck in a traffic jam.
We know it’s frustrating.
But honking your horn doesn’t help anyone.
It just makes people feel worse.
Relax, maybe even listen to a podcast!
Tip number four is for London cyclists.
Please stop riding on the pavement.
Also, stop doing all the other things you do which annoy people,
like not stopping at red traffic lights.
Yes, we know you’re saving the planet, and that’s lovely.
But you still need to obey the rules.
Oh, and this goes for e-scooters, too!
Tip number five is for residents, that’s all the people who actually live in London.
Talk to your neighbours!
We Londoners are famous for not getting to know the people who live near us.
But many of us started chatting to strangers during the COVID-19 pandemic,
and even got to know our neighbours for the first time.
It’s one of the things that helped everyone to feel better,
so don’t forget about it now!
My final tip is for tourists.
We’re very happy to have you,
but please think about the people who live and work here.
Help to make their lives easier.
Don’t walk in busy streets with enormous suitcases
or take selfies at the entrance of busy railway stations
just when commuters are trying to catch their train.
Don’t walk in big groups along crowded pavements.
You’ll soon see that local people will be more friendly!